# Jonathan Collins

New York, United States



jonathan.collins@live.com



linkedin.com/in/jonmcollins



available upon request



https://jcodes.page

## Summary

Skills | Summary

Self taught Full Stack Developer 4+ years experience working with JavaScript, React, Gatsby, NodeJS, MongoDB, Firestore, Shopify ECommerce, Jamstack, Strapi, Version Control, Software Development Life Cycle methods, and more. I've built various applications on a small team focused on feature development, user experiences, and I work with custom API creation and third party API integration. I am a dedicated problem solver and life long learner. I possess a CSM/PSM certificate from Scrum.org on agile development practices and I am pursuing certification as a CSD/PSD. I am currently learning Java and Next.is. I shifted from an established career in finance to pursue my passion for programming.

## **Experience**



#### W Software Engineer

**Lineage Logistics** 

May 2020 - Present (1 year 7 months +)

I am asked to evaluate third party software solutions for possible integration into existing stacks, frameworks, and environment I work on a small development team that integrates with functional IT personnel to provide easy to use software solutions to the less technical working groups within the company I work with complex logistical databases centered around inventory materials and product orders



### Vistex Engineer and Web Developer

Maines Paper and Food Service, Inc.

Nov 2014 - May 2020 (5 years 7 months)

Built income tracking programs within the Vistex bolt-on component of SAP - responsible for billing and tracking over 15 million in ARR

Developed the company's first Truck Tracking program using a complex Verizon API and JavaScript web interface to track, and notify, stakeholders on delivery/late delivery metrics Conceptualized and built a JavaScript/JSON web interface/database for Product Line Managers to enter contract details to be tracked via the SAP Vistex Module

#### Broker

**HSBC** 

Aug 2004 - Nov 2014 (10 years 4 months) Managed client wealth portfolios and helped to diversify wealth holdings and vehicles

Built customized portfolio analytics programs to gain better insight around client mismatches of tolerance vs instrument



Sep 1995 - Jul 1999 (3 years 11 months)

#### **Education**



#### Whitney Point High School

Diploma, Liberal Arts and Sciences, General Studies and Humanities 1994 - 1999 Regents Diploma

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



Certified ScrumMaster (CSM) - Scrum.org

517ccf0d-c666-4f77-a20e-5581b8d8bec5

#### **Skills**

JavaScript • React.js • GatsbyJS • MongoDB • Mongoose ODM • Node.js • Scrum • JAMstack · Strapi.js · Version Control

#### **Honors & Awards**



**MVP of the Year** - Maines Paper and Food Service, Inc.

Jan 2015

Received most valuable person award for creating a blueprinting program that allowed for the onboarding of multi-million dollar logistics contract for a nationally recognized chain.